Guide to the Rachel Carson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1921-79; Series I; 44; (101 boxes)
  - THE SEA AROUND US
    - Manuscripts
      - List of corrections, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 109)
      - Draft C: typescript, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 110-17)
      - Draft D: typescript, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 118-23)
      - Draft E: typescript and carbons, corrected (incomplete) (Box 7, Folder 124-29)
      - Draft F: typescript and carbons, corrected (incomplete) (Box 7, Folder 130-33)
      - "Unpublishable chapter" ("The Ocean and a Hungry World") (Box 7, Folder 134)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 135-41)
      - Page proofs, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 142-45)
      - Miscellaneous manuscript pages, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 146)
      - Endpaper sketch (Box 9, Folder 147)
      - List of chapter introductory quotations, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 148)
      - "Suggestions for Further Reading": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 149)
      - Bibliography: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 150)
      - Corrections (New American Library edition), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 151)
      - German edition: illustrations, 1953, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 152)
      - Excerpts and abridgments
        "The Sea," The New Yorker
        - Page proofs, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 153)
        - Printed copy, 1951 Jun 2-16 (Box 9, Folder 154)
        - "Birth of an Island"
          - Yale Review, 1950 Sep (Box 9, Folder 155)
          - Pageant, 1952 Jan (Box 9, Folder 156)
        - "The Shape of Ancient Seas" Nature Magazine, 1951 May (Box 9, Folder 156a)
        - "Wealth from the Salt Seas": Science Digest, 1950 Oct (Box 9, Folder 157)
        - Reader's Digest, 1951 Dec (Box 9, Folder 158)
        - Saturday Review of Literature, 1951 Jun 23 (Box 9, Folder 159)
        - Vogue, 1951 May 1 (Box 9, Folder 160)
        - Newspaper excerpts, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    - Post-publication material
      - "Origins of the Book, The Sea Around Us " (Box 9, Folder 162)
      - Reviews, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 163)
      - Reviews, 1951-52 (Box 10, Folder 165-69)
      - Responses, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 170-71)
      - Promotional material, 1951-52 (Box 10, Folder 172-77)
      - Best-seller lists, 1951-52 (Box 11, Folder 178-87)
      - Awards, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 188)
        See also: Oversize, Box 114, folder 2204
      - Saxton Memorial Trust
        - Grant application material, 1948, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 189)
        - Notices, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 190)
        - Related correspondence, 1949-50 (Box 11, Folder 191)
      - Film adaptation
        - News clippings, 1951-62 (Box 11, Folder 192)
        - Related correspondence, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 193-94)
      - TV adaptation (by Genevieve Wood), 1952 (Box 11, Folder 195)
      - Related correspondence
        - "A" general, 1950-56 (Box 12, Folder 196)
        - "B" general, 1948-59 (Box 12, Folder 197)
        - Bacon, Leonard, 1951 Jul 1 (Box 12, Folder 198)
        - "C" general, 1951-52 (Box 12, Folder 199)
        - "D" general, 1951-52 (Box 12, Folder 200)
        - "E-F" general, 1951-53 (Box 12, Folder 201)
        - Fish and Wildlife Service, U. S. Department of the Interior, 1951-53 (Box 12, Folder 202)
        - "G" general, 1951-52 (Box 12, Folder 203)
        - "H" general, 1951-61 (Box 12, Folder 204)
        - Heyerdahl, Thor, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 205)
        - "J-K" general, 1951-53 (Box 12, Folder 206)
        - "L" general, 1952-59 (Box 12, Folder 207)
        - "M" general, 1951-52 (Box 12, Folder 208)
        - Murphy, Robert Cushman (American Museum of Natural History), 1950-54 (Box 12, Folder 209)
        - "N-O" general, 1951-53 (Box 12, Folder 210)
        - Oxford University Press, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 211-17)
        - "P" general, 1951-56 (Box 12, Folder 218)
        - Pettersson, Hans, 1953-56 (Box 12, Folder 219)
        - "R" general, 1951-52 (Box 12, Folder 220)
        - Rutledge, Archibald, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 221)
        - "S" general, 1951-53 (Box 12, Folder 222)
        - Simon and Schuster, 1949-52 (Box 12, Folder 223)
        - "T" general, 1951-54 (Box 12, Folder 224)
        - "U-V" general, 1951-53 (Box 12, Folder 225)
        - "W" general, 1949-60 (Box 12, Folder 226)
        - "X-Z" general, 1950-53 (Box 12, Folder 227)
        - Fan mail
          - New Yorker serialization, 1951-53 (Box 13, Folder 228-39)
          - Book publication, 1951-62 (Box 14, Folder 240-62)
        - Scrapbook, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 263)
        - Miscellaneous, 1952-63 (Box 15, Folder 264)
  - THE SEA AROUND US (Young Readers' Edition)
    - Manuscripts
      - Notes
        - General, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 265)
        - Notes for captions: holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 266)
        - Notes on illustrations: holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 267)
        - "Geologic Time Scale", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 268)
      - Typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 15, Folder 269-74)
      - Suggested corrections, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 275)
      - "Schedule of Illustrations", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 276-77)
      - Layout proofs
        See: Oversize, Box 115, folder 2205
      - Galley proofs
        See: Oversize, Box 115, folder 2206
    - Post-publication material
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 278)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 279)
      - Related correspondence (Box 16, Folder 280-82)
  - THE SEA AROUND US (Revised edition)
    - Research material, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 283-91)
    - Manuscripts
      - Preface: holograph and typescript (Box 16, Folder 292-93)
      - Appendix: holograph and typescript (Box 16, Folder 294)
      - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 295)
      - Revisions: holograph, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 296)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 297-305)
    - Post-publication material
      - Reviews, 1960-61 (Box 17, Folder 306)
      - Promotional material, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 307)
    - Related correspondence
      - "A-M" general, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 308)
      - Oxford University Press, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 309)
      - "P-Z" general, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 310)
    - Miscellaneous [including regular edition material], n.d. (Box 17, Folder 311-16)
  - THE EDGE OF THE SEA
    - Research material
      - Articles and pamphlets (Box 18, Folder 317)
      - "A-B" general, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 318)
      - Bigelow, Henry B., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 319)
      - "C-H" general, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 320)
      - Hines, Robert, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 321)
      - "L-M" general, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 322)
      - Moore, Hilary B., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 323)
      - "N-S" general, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 324)
      - Scripps Institution of Oceanography, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 325)
      - Stephenson, T. A., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 326)
      - "T" general, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 327)
      - Taylor, William Randolph (Box 18, Folder 328)
      - "W" general, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 329)
      - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 330)
    - Manuscript material
      - Notes
        - "Preliminary Notes and Drafts" (Box 18, Folder 331-34)
        - Field notes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 335-36)
        - Subjects
          - Coral, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 337)
          - Dunes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 338)
          - Ecology, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 339)
          - Geology, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 340-41)
          - High-tide rocks, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 342)
          - Lambinaria zone, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 343)
          - Life on shore, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 344)
          - Phyla, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 345-47)
          - Preface, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 348)
          - Salt marsh, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 349)
          - Sand (Box 19, Folder 350)
          - "Strays from Offshore Waters", n.d. (Box 19, Folder 351)
          - Tide pools, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 352)
          - "Who's Who" (classifications), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 353)
        - Notes to Chapter IV, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 354-55)
        - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 356)
        - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 357)
        - Notecards, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 358)
      - Draft A: holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 359)
      - Draft B: holograph and typescript, corrected, with notes (incomplete) (Box 21, Folder 360-76)
      - Draft B: holograph and typescript, corrected, with notes (incomplete) (Box 22, Folder 377-86)
      - Draft C: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 22, Folder 387-408)
      - Draft C: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 23, Folder 409-27)
      - "Intermediate Drafts," with carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 428-38)
      - Late (final?) draft, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 439-47)
      - "Printer's Script", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 448-54)
      - Galley proofs, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 455-61)
      - Page proofs, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 462-64)
      - Illustrations, n.d. (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 465-72)
      - Captions for illustrations, 1955, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 473-74)
      - New Yorker serialization
        - Typescript, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 475-78)
        - Page proofs, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 479-80)
        - Printed copy, 1955 Aug 20-27 (Box 27, Folder 481-82)
      - Galley proofs (paperback edition), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 483-84)
    - Post-publication material
      - Review list, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 485)
      - Reviews, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 486-90)
      - Scrapbook (reviews, notices, etc.), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 491)
      - Best-seller lists, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 492)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 493)
      - "Trade Samples" list, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 494)
      - Awards, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 495)
      - Related correspondence
        - "A-F" general, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 496)
        - Frey, Gudrun, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 497)
        - Guggenheim Foundation, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 498)
        - "H" general, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 499)
        - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1951-57 (Box 29, Folder 500-14)
        - "J-W" general, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 515)
        - Fan mail, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 516)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 517-18)
  - SILENT SPRING
    - Research material
      - Subject files
        - Air pollution, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 519-21)
        - Aldrin, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 522)
        - Antibiotics, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 523)
        - Arsenic, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 524)
        - Arsenic in cigarettes, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 525)
        - Aviation spraying, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 526)
        - Bees, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 527)
        - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 528-29)
        - Biological controls, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 530-33)
        - Biological controls: radiation, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 534-35)
        - Birds, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 536-41)
        - Cancer, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 542-53)
        - Cancer (Hueper studies), n.d. (Box 32, Folder 554-59)
        - Chlordane, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 560)
        - Clear Lake, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 561)
        - Conservation: general, 1957, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 562)
        - Consumer reports, 1952-56 (Box 32, Folder 563)
        - Crustaceans, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 564)
        - Cytology, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 565)
        - DDT, 1946-60, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 566-67)
        - Deaths among children, 1963, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 568)
        - Dieldrin, 1959, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 569-70)
        - Disease: general, 1960, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 571)
        - Dutch Elm disease, 1960-63, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 572-74)
        - Eagles, 1957-61 (Box 33, Folder 575-76)
        - Encephalitis, 1962, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 577)
        - Evolution, 1945-63, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 578-80)
        - Fire ant, 1958-62, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 581-84)
        - Fish, 1948-61, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 585-97)
        - Fish kills, 1956-61 (Box 33, Folder 598)
        - Food, 1962-63 (Box 34, Folder 599)
        - Food and drugs, 1954-60, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 600-01)
        - Food contamination, 1955-61, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 602)
        - Food surplus, 1959, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 603)
        - Genetics, 1946-61 (Box 34, Folder 604-06)
        - Gypsy moth, 1952-63 (Box 34, Folder 607)
        - Hepatitis, 1955, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 608)
        - Herbicides, 1951-63 (Box 34, Folder 609-11)
        - Insect control by sound, 1958-59 (Box 34, Folder 612)
        - Insect hormones, 1958, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 613)
        - Insect sterilization, 1959, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 614)
        - Insecticide tolerance, 1957-60 (Box 34, Folder 615)
        - International Union for the Protection of Nature: bulletins, 1950-61 (Box 34, Folder 616)
        - Japanese beetles, 1950-61 (Box 34, Folder 617)
        - Leukemia, 1946-51 (Box 34, Folder 618)
        - Livestock, 1951-63 (Box 34, Folder 619)
        - Malaria, 1952-59 (Box 34, Folder 620)
        - Mass spraying, 1958-60, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 621)
        - Mediterranean fruit fly, 1956-59 (Box 35, Folder 622)
        - Milk contamination, 1950-60 (Box 35, Folder 623-24)
        - Mosquito control, 1948-60 (Box 35, Folder 625)
        - Mouse control, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 626)
        - National Wildlife Federation, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 627)
        - Normal soil, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 628)
        - Nutrition and health foods, 1957-62 (Box 35, Folder 629)
        - Occupational hazards and economic poisons, 1957-59 (Box 35, Folder 630)
        - Orchard pest control, 1954-61 (Box 35, Folder 631)
        - Organic phosphate pesticides, 1949-63 (Box 35, Folder 632-34)
        - Parks and wildlife refuges, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 635)
        - Pest Control Review Board, 1961-62 (Box 35, Folder 636)
        - Pesticides: general, 1951-63 (Box 35, Folder 637-38)
        - Pesticides: agricultural use, 1958-60 (Box 35, Folder 639)
        - Pesticides: effect on hunting and fishing (Box 35, Folder 640)
        - Pesticides for lawns, 1958-61 (Box 35, Folder 641)
        - Pesticides: lawsuits, 1958-59 (Box 35, Folder 642)
        - Pesticides: regulation, 1959-60 (Box 36, Folder 643)
        - Pesticide resistance, 1954-63, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 644-45)
        - Pesticide safety violations, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 646)
        - Photos: miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 647)
        - Physiology, 1948-61 (Box 36, Folder 648-49)
        - Plant resistance, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 650)
        - Potentiation, 1958-62, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 651)
        - Radiation, 1955-63 (Box 36, Folder 652-53)
        - Range plants, 1955-61 (Box 36, Folder 654)
        - Roadside spraying, 1952-61 (Box 36, Folder 655-56)
        - Sea lamprey control, 1958-59, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 657)
        - Seed treatment, 1957-63 (Box 36, Folder 658)
        - Selenium, 1958-61 (Box 36, Folder 659)
        - Sevin, 1959-63, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 660)
        - Soil contamination, 1951-62 (Box 36, Folder 661-62)
        - Space exploration, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 663)
        - Sterility, 1952-61, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 664)
        - Systemic insecticide, 1953-61 (Box 36, Folder 665)
        - Teflon hazards, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 666)
        - Terramycin, 1959, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 667)
        - Tobacco insects, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 668)
        - Tolerances, 1957 Oct 1 (Box 37, Folder 669)
        - Water pollution, 1956-62 (Box 37, Folder 670)
        - Weather, 1957-58 (Box 37, Folder 671)
        - Weed control, 1960, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 672)
        - Wildlife, 1952-62, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 673-74)
        - Miscellaneous, 1946-61 (Box 37, Folder 675-79)
      - Chapter source materials
        - Chapter I, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 680)
        - Chapter II, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 681)
        - Chapter IV, 1958-63 (Box 38, Folder 682-84)
        - Chapter V, 1956-60 (Box 38, Folder 685-87)
        - Chapter VI, 1953-61, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 688-94)
        - Chapter IX, 1949-61 (Box 38, Folder 695-98)
        - Chapter X, 1955-61, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 699-703)
        - Chapter XI, 1954-61, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 704-06)
        - Chapter XII, 1950-61 (Box 39, Folder 707-08)
        - Chapter XIII, 1953-61, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 709-12)
        - Chapter XIV, 1946-62 (Box 39, Folder 713-15)
        - Chapter XIV, 1941-61 (Box 40, Folder 716-19)
        - Chapters XV-XVI, 1946-61 (Box 40, Folder 720-26)
        - Chapter XVII, 1949-62 (Box 40, Folder 727-33)
        - "List of Principal Sources", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 734-35)
      - Author files
        - "A" general, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 736)
        - "B" general, 1951-63, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 737)
        - "C" general, 1950-63 (Box 41, Folder 738-39)
        - "D" general, 1948-59 (Box 41, Folder 740)
        - "E" general, 1960-62 (Box 41, Folder 741)
        - "F" general, 1953-62 (Box 41, Folder 742)
        - "G" general, 1943-57, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 743)
        - "H" general, 1951-62 (Box 41, Folder 744)
        - "J-K" general, 1952-58, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 745)
        - "L" general, 1948-59 (Box 41, Folder 746)
        - "M-N" general, 1957-63 (Box 41, Folder 747)
        - "O-R" general, 1946-59 (Box 41, Folder 748)
        - "S" general, 1956-59, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 749)
        - "T" general, 1945-62 (Box 41, Folder 750)
        - "U-V" general, 1954-63, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 751)
      - Research correspondence
        - "A" general, 1958-61 (Box 42, Folder 752)
        - American Museum of Natural History, 1954-61 (Box 42, Folder 753)
        - Animal Welfare Institute, 1960-65 (Box 42, Folder 754)
        - "B" general, 1958-62 (Box 42, Folder 755-56)
        - Balch, R. E., 1958-59 (Box 42, Folder 757)
        - Barnes, Irston, 1960-61 (Box 42, Folder 758)
        - Belt, Charles Banks, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 759)
        - Biesele, John J., 1960 (Box 42, Folder 760)
        - Bioferm Corporation, 1959-62 (Box 42, Folder 761)
        - Biskind, Morton, 1959-62 (Box 42, Folder 762)
        - Boyle, Evelyn J., 1959-61 (Box 42, Folder 763)
        - Briejèr, C. J., 1958-62 (Box 42, Folder 764)
        - Briggs, John D., 1958-61 (Box 42, Folder 765)
        - Brown, A. W. A., 1959-63 (Box 42, Folder 766)
        - Brown, William L., Jr., 1958-62 (Box 42, Folder 767)
        - "C" general, 1958-62 (Box 42, Folder 768)
        - California: Department of Public Health, 1959-60 (Box 42, Folder 769)
        - Canada: Department of Agriculture, 1961-62 (Box 42, Folder 770)
        - Committee on Natural Resources of the Democratic Advisory Council, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 771)
        - Conservation Foundation, 1958-61 (Box 42, Folder 772)
        - Cottam, Clarence, 1958-62 (Box 42, Folder 773-74)
        - "D" general, 1959-63 (Box 42, Folder 775)
        - Darling, Lois Darling, Louis, 1961-62 (Box 42, Folder 776-77)
        - Douglas, William O., 1962 (Box 42, Folder 778)
        - "E" general, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 779)
        - Egler, Frank, 1955-62 (Box 43, Folder 780-82)
        - Entomological Research Society, 1962-63 (Box 43, Folder 783)
        - Errington, Paul, 1961-62 (Box 43, Folder 784)
        - Etter, Alfred, 1959-62 (Box 43, Folder 785)
          See also: Box 83, folder 1460
        - "F" general, 1959-62 (Box 43, Folder 786)
        - Fairfax Biological Laboratory, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 787)
        - Federation of Homemakers, 1962-63 (Box 43, Folder 788)
        - Fisheries Research Board of Canada, 1959-62 (Box 43, Folder 789)
        - Florida Audubon Society, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 790)
        - Free, Ann Cottrell, 1959-62 (Box 43, Folder 791)
        - "G" general, 1958-62 (Box 43, Folder 792)
        - "H" general, 1958-62 (Box 43, Folder 793)
        - Hargraves, Malcolm M. (Mayo Clinic), 1958-62 (Box 43, Folder 794-95)
        - Hickey, Joseph, 1959-61 (Box 43, Folder 796)
        - Hueper, W. C. (National Cancer Institute), 1960-61 (Box 43, Folder 797)
        - "I" general, 1959-61 (Box 43, Folder 798)
        - Illinois: State Natural History Survey Division, 1960-62 (Box 43, Folder 799)
        - "J" general, 1959-61 (Box 43, Folder 800)
        - "K-L" general, 1959-62 (Box 43, Folder 801)
        - Laird, Marshall (World Health Organization), 1961 (Box 43, Folder 802)
        - League of Women Voters, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 803)
        - Light, Israel, 1959-62 (Box 43, Folder 804)
        - Linduska, Joseph P., 1958-61 (Box 43, Folder 805)
        - Lorentz, Pare, 1960-62, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 806)
          See also: Box 42, folder 771
        - "M" general, 1958-62 (Box 43, Folder 807)
        - Massachusetts Audubon Society, 1959-60 (Box 43, Folder 808)
        - Ministry of Agriculture, Fisheries, and Food (British), 1959-62 (Box 43, Folder 809)
        - Murphy, Grace Murphy, Robert Cushman, 1958-59 (Box 43, Folder 810)
        - "N" general, 1958-63 (Box 43, Folder 811)
        - National Audubon Society, 1958-62 (Box 43, Folder 812-13)
        - The New Yorker, 1959-62 (Box 43, Folder 814)
        - Nickell, Walter, 1958-59 (Box 43, Folder 815)
        - "O" general, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 816)
        - "P" general, 1959-63 (Box 44, Folder 817)
        - Patou, Klaus, 1961-62 (Box 44, Folder 818)
        - Peters, Harold S.
          See: National Audubon Society, Box 43, folder 812-813
        - Potts, W. H., 1959-60 (Box 44, Folder 819)
        - "R" general, 1959-63 (Box 44, Folder 820)
        - Reader's Digest, 1945-60 (Box 44, Folder 821)
        - Rudd, Robert L., 1958-59 (Box 44, Folder 822)
        - "S" general, 1958-62 (Box 44, Folder 823)
        - Satterlea, Henry S., 1958-61 (Box 44, Folder 824)
        - Schneiderman, Howard, 1958-61 (Box 44, Folder 825)
        - Scott, Ruth (The Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania), 1961-62 (Box 44, Folder 826)
        - Shepard, Paul, 1959-60 (Box 44, Folder 827)
        - Spock, Marjorie, 1958-66 (Box 44, Folder 828-29)
        - "T" general, 1958-60 (Box 44, Folder 830)
        - Tarzwell, Clarence, 1959-62 (Box 44, Folder 831)
        - "U" general, 1958-60 (Box 44, Folder 832)
        - United States: Department of Agriculture, 1958-62 (Box 44, Folder 833)
        - United States: Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1959-62 (Box 44, Folder 834)
        - United States: Department of the Interior, 1959-63 (Box 44, Folder 835)
        - "V" general, 1960-62 (Box 44, Folder 836)
        - "W" general, 1958-63 (Box 44, Folder 837)
        - Wallace, George J., 1958-62 (Box 44, Folder 838)
        - White, E. B., 1958 (Box 44, Folder 839)
        - Wilderness Society (Olaus Maurie), 1960-62 (Box 44, Folder 840)
        - Wilson, Edward O., 1958-59 (Box 44, Folder 841)
        - Wilson, G. B., 1959-60 (Box 44, Folder 842)
        - "Y" general, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 843)
    - Manuscripts
      - Notes
        - Aldrin, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 844)
        - Cancer, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 845)
        - Carbamates, 1959-60, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 846)
        - Contamination of food, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 847)
        - DDD, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 848)
        - DDT controversy, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 849-56)
        - Dieldrin, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 857)
        - Genetics and cytology (Box 45, Folder 858)
        - Health hazards, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 859)
        - Heptachlor, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 860)
        - Herbicides, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 861-62)
        - Insects, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 863)
        - Insecticides, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 864)
        - Insecticides: effect on crops, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 865)
        - Insecticides: soil residues, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 866)
        - Lindane (Box 45, Folder 867)
        - Medical considerations, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 868-73)
        - Medical considerations, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 874-78)
        - Methoxychlor, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 879)
        - Milk contamination, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 880)
        - Organic phosphates, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 881)
        - Phenols, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 882)
        - "Philosophy", n.d. (Box 46, Folder 883)
        - Soils, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 884-85)
        - Soils and plants (Box 46, Folder 886)
        - Systematic insecticides, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 887)